<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<recenzije>
<recenzija><id>1</id><naslov>Samsung Galaxy S7 edge review</naslov>
<slika>uploads/slika1.jpg</slika>
<tekst>SAMSUNG GALAXY S7 EDGE – SCREEN
5.5-inch quad-HD panel, dual curved edges

If the design of the S7 Edge is stunning, then the same word can be used to describe the display. Not a whole lot has changed from the outgoing flagships, but this still holds up as the best screen on a smartphone for a number of reasons.

First up is the sheer amount of detail here. Samsung didn’t try and go all-out with a 4K display, but really when quad-HD (that’s 2560 x 1440) looks this good I don’t think there’s much of a need for more pixels. Maybe it would help make VR even better with the Gear VR headset, but that’ll probably come next year.


Read more at http://www.trustedreviews.com/samsung-galaxy-s7-edge-review#O8wdFKgCmSkZhUlo.99</tekst></recenzija>

<recenzija><id>2</id><naslov>Apple iPhone 7 review</naslov><slika>uploads/slika5.jpg</slika><tekst>The iPhone 7 and 7 Plus are deeply unusual devices. They are full of aggressive breaks from convention while wrapped in cases that look almost exactly like their two direct predecessors. Even that continuity of design is a break from convention; after almost a decade of Apple’s steady two-year iPhone update pattern, merely retaining the same design for a third straight year plays against expectations.&#13;
&#13;
Inside that case, everything else about the iPhone 7 is a decisive statement about the future. The dual cameras on the iPhone 7 Plus promise to usher in a new era in mobile photography. The iconic iPhone home button is no longer a physical button, but instead a sophisticated ballet of pressure sensors and haptic vibration motors that simulate the feel of a button. The new A10 Fusion processor blends two high-power cores that rival laptop performance with two low-power cores that combine with a much larger battery to extend run time by up to two hours.&#13;
&#13;
And, yes, Apple has removed the headphone jack.&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DmQgcHjJuKo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</tekst></recenzija><recenzija><id>3</id><naslov>Sony Xperia Z5 Review</naslov><slika>uploads/slika6.jpg</slika><tekst>When it first launched, the Sony Xperia Z5 represented the culmination of 18 months of incremental improvements for Sony's range of Xperia smartphones, and a year on, it remains one of our favourite smartphones.

That's despite the appearance of two other versions of the Z5: the diminutive Z5 Compact, and the slightly larger Z5 Premium, which is almost identical, the somewhat superfluous 4K screen aside. And then there's the more recent Sony Xperia X and Sony Xperia XA, two phones that would seem to signify a move away from the Z series as the firms smartphone standard bearer.

All four phones offer a variation on the Xperia theme, but none of them quite manages to match the Xperia Z5's combination of superb design and all-round competence.

Image of Sony Xperia Z5 (white)	Sony Xperia Z5 (white)	
327.00
Buy now

Sony Xperia Z5 review: Design

That's why, for me, it's the Xperia Z5 that deserves its place at the head of Sony's smartphone range, and it all starts with that gorgeous, almost-all-glass design. Although Sony has stuck with the design language that has stood it in such good stead over the past few years (so the phone keeps the trademark Xperia glass-slabbed front and back and squared-off profile, and it remains both water- and dust-resistant to IP68), it is different and chock full of refinements that really make a difference.



The aesthetic alterations are the most subtle: there's a new engraved Xperia logo on the left edge; the Xperia Z5's metal frame has been squared off ever so slightly; and Sony has swapped the glossy glass rear for a smooth-to-the-touch frosted glass plate. Surrounding the screen at the very edge is a slightly raised lip, a design feature intended to prevent the phone slipping off inclined surfaces. And in each of the white, Graphite Black, gold and green colour options, it looks simply gorgeous.

As with all glass-backed phones, however, if you buy one of these, you'll need to be careful how you handle it. I dropped my review sample from the height of around 30cm onto some gravel, and it shattered the rear into thousands of tiny shards. That wouldn't have happened to a phone with a plastic or metal rear casing. I'd advise using a case, or at the very least a screen protector applied to the rear, just to be on the safe side.

The biggest departure in design terms, however, is the look of the power button. Sonys trademark protruding chrome-effect circle, which has been around for years, has now been replaced by an elongated lozenge, slightly inset from the edge to prevent you accidentally pressing it.



This seems a frivolous change on the surface, but theres considerably more substance to it than first meets the eye, since  the button hides one of the Z5s big new features: a fingerprint reader.

So far, most smartphones with one of these components have opted to pop it beneath the home button, or on the rear, both approaches that have their problems. The front reader can be difficult to reach with a one-handed grip, and you run the risk of dropping the phone because you're holding it right near the bottom edge. Rear readers are better for one-handed use, but you can't use them to unlock a phone while it's sitting on a desk.

The Sony Xperia Z5's is the best compromise I've come across so far. It can be used on a desk or in your hand, and its positioning is such that it naturally falls under your finger or thumb when you pick it up. It works reliably and quickly, too. It's the best-thought-out fingerprint reader yet.

The one design change Im not entirely sold, however, on is the repositioning of the volume rocker from just next to the power button to lower on the right edge, right above the camera shutter. It's a baffling design decision and makes it tricky to adjust the volume one-handed with your thumb. </tekst></recenzija></recenzije>
