<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<novosti>
<novost><id>1</id><naslov>Samsung Galaxy S7 and S7 edge start receiving November security patch</naslov><slika>uploads/slika3.jpg</slika><tekst>T-Mobile has started pushing out a new update to Samsung Galaxy S7 and S7 edge smartphones on its network. Arriving as software version G930TUVU4APK1 and G935TUVU4APK1, respectively, and weighing in at over 80MB, the update brings along Android security patch for the month of November.
 As is usually the case with OTA roll outs, it may take some time for the update to hit your device. Meanwhile, if you feel impatient, you can manually check for the update by heading to your handset's Settings menu.</tekst><slikavijest>slika8.jpg</slikavijest></novost>
<novost><id>2</id><naslov>Apple may freshen up its iPhone 7 lineup with a shiny new ‘Jet White’ color</naslov><slika>uploads/slika10.png</slika><tekst>Appple initially announced its new and improved iPhone 7 will be available in five color options: Silver, Gold, Rose Gold, Matte Black and Jet Black. But it seems the Cupertino giant isn’t quite done introducing additional colors to its lineup.
The Big A is reportedly planning to refresh its iPhone 7 lineup with a new ‘Jet White’ color option, Japanese news outlet Mac Otakara reports.
The report makes no mention of when Apple might add the sixth color to its catalogue, but it speculates it will be available for both models – the standard iPhone 7 as well as the boosted 7 Plus.
While Mac Otakara has accurately leaked information about upcoming Apple products in the past, the Japanese publication warns its source “may not be reliable” this time around – so don’t get too excited just yet.
Apple enthusiasts are well-known for sketching recreational mockups of some of the company’s most popular products. It wouldn’t be entirely out of the ordinary if it turns out the Jet White iPhone 7 rumor is merely another fan-made concept – much like this mockup of the AirPods in Jet Black.
</tekst><slikavijest>slika9.jpg</slikavijest></novost>


<novost><id>3</id><naslov>Xiaomi Mi 6 is now said to become official on February 6, out in March</naslov><slika>uploads/slika12.jpg</slika><tekst>Yesterday a few different reports originating in China brought us some conflicting information regarding Xiaomi's upcoming Mi 6, and more specifically when we can expect it to launch. One source was convinced the announcement would take place on February 14, while others disputed that claiming it was delayed to April.
And now here we are one day later when yet another date is being mentioned in the rumors. Xiaomi is now said to unveil the Mi 6 at a special event on February 6 (what a fitting date), with sales scheduled to begin at some point in March.
The previous reports that spoke about a delay to April claimed that had to do with Samsung not being able to produce enough Snapdragon 835 chipsets for Qualcomm. As this is the SoC that's going to be in the Mi 6 (and the Galaxy S8 too), you can see how low yields on its production could result in delays for smartphones sporting it.
However, today another Chinese analyst chimed in on Weibo saying that the yield issues aren't as bad as made out to be in the media, and Xiaomi has already started receiving shipments of the SD835 for the Mi 6. As such, the phone will be announced on February 6 and it will go on sale in March, though only limited quantities may be available for the first few weeks.</tekst></novost></novosti>
